MUHAMMAD TAHA

in: MUHAMMADTAHANASIR

: MUHAMMADTAHANASIR | m.tahanasir.cs@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm currently a Sophomore at FAST NUCES studying Computer Science. I've built a strong coding base and get the ins and outs of object-oriented programming (OOP), currently in DSA learning Era. I've also got hands-on experience with Python. I've faced some tough spots in my studies, but I've pushed through them. This has made me tough and focused.

WORK HISTORY

TECHNOHACKS EDUTECH OFFICIAL

Python Developer Intern | TechnoHacks EduTech Official, Nashik | October 2023 - January 2024

• During this internship, I gained valuable insights into Python programming, which improved my problem-solving skills. Additionally, I completed several small projects during this internship, which gave me a deeper understanding of programming in Python, honed my skills, and expanded my knowledge.

CODSOFT

Python Programming Intern | CodSoft, West Bengal | September 2023 - October 2023

- During my CodSoft Python Programming Internship, I gained valuable insights into various aspects
 of Python programming. I learned to apply Python to real-world scenarios, enhancing my problemsolving skills.
- In addition to these core learnings, this facet of the internship imparted a comprehensive understanding of how to proficiently push projects to GitHub and navigate the various functionalities of this essential platform.
- Overall, the internship enriched my Python programming knowledge, honed my practical skills, and provided me with a deeper understanding of programming in Python.

HEADSTARTER

Software Engineering Fellow | July 2024-Present

- Engineered and launched five AI-driven projects over five weeks, utilizing React JS, Next.js, Firebase, Clerk, and Vercel, adhering to agile methodologies with weekly sprints, and implementing CI/CD practices for iterative releases.
- Collaborated with a team of three to design and develop an interactive customer support agent using Next.js, incorporating a custom RAG pipeline with OpenAI and Pinecone, enabling responses based on a company's knowledge base.
- Partnered with three other Fellows to create and deploy a SaaS product that generates dynamic flashcards on any topic using Llama 3.1 LLM through the Groq API, and integrated a paywall system with custom pricing plans via the Stripe API.
- Developed and integrated a web scraper that automatically pulls data from Rate My Professor, updates a Pinecone index, and links to a RAG pipeline using LangChain and OpenAI GPT-4o for delivering timely and relevant user responses.

- Successfully scaled each web app to support over 200 users, continuously improving based on user feedback.
- Engaged in weekly sessions with engineers from leading organizations including Google, Y Combinator, Stanford, Amazon, and various venture-backed startups.

SKILLS

- Python
- C, C++
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Abode Lightroom, Illustrator, Photoshop
- MySQL
- MongoDB

EDUCATION

DEGREE OBTAINED (BCSC)

FAST- National University of Computer & Emerging Sciences

2023 - current

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Software Engineering Professional

NED Academy - NED University of Engineering & Technology, Karachi

Credential ID: 19073 Show Credential

Career Essentials in Generative AI by Microsoft and LinkedIn

Microsoft

Show Credential

Object Oriented Programming Specialization

Goldsmiths, University of London

Credential ID: 8NFMPTN5H4SM Show Credential